Tylar Hart

Email: tylarjhart00@outlook.com Mobile: +61 403 761 009

CAREER OBJECTIVE

3rd year Data Engineering student pursuing a 6-month internship in which I can gain valuable work experience. I am passionate about learning new and interesting ideas and concepts. I hope to develop my team skills further and learn new skills on the job.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) (Data)
Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice
University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

Mar 2019 - Nov 2023 (Expected)

Feb 2013 - Nov 2018

Current GPA (7 Point scale): 6.09

- High Distinction in Network Fundamentals
- High Distinction in Sensing, Actuation and Control
- High Distinction in Physical Modelling
- High Distinction in Data Systems
- High Distinction in Applications Programming
- High Distinction in Internet of Things

NSW High School Certificate Broughton Anglican College

ATAR: 82.3

•	E3 in Mathematics Extension 1	2018
•	Band 5 in Physics	2018
•	Band 5 in Software Design and Development	2018
•	STEM scholarship for Years 11 and 12	2018, 2017
•	Distinction in the UNSW Science Competition	2018, 2016
•	1st in Information and Software Technology	2016, 2015
•	1 st in Software Applications	2015
•	Credit in the Australian Mathematics Competition	2017, 2015, 2013

STUDENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Sensory Substitution for the Visually Impaired University of Technology Sydney (UTS)

Jul 2019 - Jun 2020

Designed and developed a program utilising python and ROS to aid the visually impaired in navigation and recognition of texts, objects, and faces. As well as develop a tool using python and SQL to store data to later be used to predict battery life, and user requests.

Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering Work Experience University of Sydney (USYD)

Introduced to different and new processes within the engineering field, studying how various processes work and are controlled through computer technology.

Work Experience Program

26th - 30th Sep 2016

Academy of Interactive Entertainment (AIE)

Designed and developed a small board game, going through the process of game design, as well as working with Unity, Adobe Photoshop, and Maya.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCES

Engineers Without Borders Challenge (Team Leader)

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

Developed a on paper prototype for a mobile communications application between WaterAid and Timor-Leste. Directed the team towards an appropriate goal that was achieved, whilst also making sure everyone within the team was on time with tasks.

NSW Rural Fire Service Secondary Schools Cadet Program

Oct 2016 - Nov 2016

Established leadership skills by leading a team of peers through firefighting drills as well as understanding the fundamentals of different fires and how to control them.

Year 3 Math Buddies (Tutor)

Feb 2015 - Dec 2017

Tutored a small group of year 3 students the basics of mathematics through puzzles and math-oriented games.

TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

Leadership Skills: Exhibited through leadership experiences, displayed above. I am able to take lead and will, given I have enough expertise in the field of development.

Team Skills: Presented across the academic achievement of group-based project subjects, achieving distinctions.

Communication Skills: Demonstrated through the tutoring of year 3 students, I can communicate relatively hard to understand concepts in a simple manner.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Skills: Python (Competent), Java (Competent), C (Competent),

ROS (Fundamental), MATLAB (Basic), SQL(Basic)

Software: Microsoft Office (Competent), Unity (Basic), Knime (Fundamental),

RIMS (Fundamental)

Licenses/Certificates: RSA, RFS Certification

REFEREES

References available upon request